<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>The Gauntlet Forums - Latest posts</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com</link>
    <description>Latest posts</description>
      <item>
        <title>The Future of the Forums</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@shane]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p><em><a href="https://tinyurl.com/TheFutureOfTheForums" rel="nofollow noopener">https://tinyurl.com/TheFutureOfTheForums</a></em></p>
<aside class="onebox googledocs">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1vR6Ygx_2ngmRYFh2zAwkKanl21VYRqV5SshCaapQ57c/preview" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">docs.google.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1vR6Ygx_2ngmRYFh2zAwkKanl21VYRqV5SshCaapQ57c/preview" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener"><span class="googledocs-onebox-logo g-docs-logo"></span></a>

<h3><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1vR6Ygx_2ngmRYFh2zAwkKanl21VYRqV5SshCaapQ57c/preview" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">The Future of the Forums</a></h3>

<p>You are probably wondering: Hey, why can’t I login? Why do things look strange?  The Management of The Gauntlet has made some decisions recently that make it impossible for the Admins of the Forums to continue their (unpaid) work for them in all good...</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
 ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-future-of-the-forums/3914/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 19:46:38 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21529</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>The 7-3-1 Technique</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@WillP]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <div><div class="short-header-page  wsite-theme-light  wsite-page-blog wsite-blog-post"></div></div>
<hr>
<small>This is a companion discussion topic for the original entry at <a href="https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/the-7-3-1-technique?fbclid=IwAR2WrVcssaCSQ3BHzZm6N6IMUlBYzWLt3_yhg3jLEKNFPLPQYFL1ZD3YFSE">https://www.gauntlet-rpg.com/blog/the-7-3-1-technique?fbclid=IwAR2WrVcssaCSQ3BHzZm6N6IMUlBYzWLt3_yhg3jLEKNFPLPQYFL1ZD3YFSE</a></small> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-7-3-1-technique/3913/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21528</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Seeking Feedback - Hesitation at the Gate</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Axxroytovu]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I’m a huge Tarot nut so I had to chime in here. Definitely interested in seeing where this game goes.</p>
<ul>
<li>I totally agree with <a class="mention" href="/u/dominik">@dominik</a>, you need a hook that tells me what the game is about. Is this a horror game, an adventure fantasy game, or a mystery investigation game? Having some examples of play and maybe an example module would be super useful.</li>
<li>I love your section on the different types of magic, and you’ve inspired me to write my own version of that for games that I’m working on.</li>
<li>Have you read the game The Sword, the Crown, and the Unspeakable Power? It has a really good section on political fantasy world building and you could probably take some ideas from there.</li>
<li>In terms of formatting, I’ve found that it’s often helpful to have the rules set up in the order: Basic game concepts (glossary, general example of play, resolution rules), character creation, specific rules, setting. There are some exceptions but I’ve found that this is at least a good starting point for getting everything into an easy to follow organization.</li>
<li>I get where you’re coming from with IP, but it isn’t that mechanically different than XP and might just be a barrier to entry.</li>
<li>It’s hard to understand Arts during character creation. One thing that I’ve found to be super helpful is to put a copy of the character sheet at the start of the “building your character” section, so that people have a reference of “Ok, I just fill in these 5 bubbles for arts” and don’t have to keep flipping back and forth to the big section in the back…</li>
<li>The functions of the great works are interesting, but would link to the world much better if they had some kind of name or “flavor” to them. If I pick the “The trump suit is cups” function, what does that look like? If it had a name as simple as “Aura of the Mind,” and a description like “The item projects a field of energy that enhances the mental focus of those within it,” then I at least have some idea of what this item will look like or how it fits in with the world.</li>
</ul>
<p>It has a lot of promise. If you’re interested in playtesting I’d totally be interested in trying this out.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/seeking-feedback-hesitation-at-the-gate/3805/12</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 18:11:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21526</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I heart World of Dungeons 1979 (let’s read them hacks &amp; drifts)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Bryan_Mullins]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p><a class="mention" href="/u/tam">@Tam</a><br>
Thanks for linking in the most recent copy! I see my cut / paste link game is off. I’m really struggling with posting here in a technical sense…fixed that link. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/upside_down_face.png?v=9" title=":upside_down_face:" class="emoji" alt=":upside_down_face:"></p>
<p>Even if it’s only a WIP, I like what you’re doing. Collecting a lot of really instructive best practices and guidance in one spot. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/fire.png?v=9" title=":fire:" class="emoji" alt=":fire:"><img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/metal.png?v=9" title=":metal:" class="emoji" alt=":metal:"></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-heart-world-of-dungeons-1979-let-s-read-them-hacks-drifts/3910/4</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 17:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21525</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I heart World of Dungeons 1979 (let’s read them hacks &amp; drifts)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Tam]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I love WoDu hacks!!!</p>
<p>My work in progress, on a kinda fuller version, if anyone’s interested:</p>
<aside class="onebox googledrive">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1d5HphGYKjhDtFnPlEUKu-FcFJ88UlNnX/view?usp=drive_open" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">drive.google.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    
<div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/362;"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9b1d96810c7c6f2d5bdb02ac1f210893f9066186.png" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1d5HphGYKjhDtFnPlEUKu-FcFJ88UlNnX/view?usp=drive_open" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">wodu-wip-Apr-06.pdf</a></h3>

<p>Google Drive file.</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p>Definitely not complete, very much a WIP, but it should be fully attributed and it’s playtested solidly at my own table on parts of Stonehell and plenty of dungeons of my own devising.</p>
<p>I feel like any parts you loved must probably be from one of the other hacks, but I do think it goes together pretty well. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/smiley.png?v=9" title=":smiley:" class="emoji" alt=":smiley:"> Just hit me up on Discord if you want templates for LaTeX, always happy to share.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-heart-world-of-dungeons-1979-let-s-read-them-hacks-drifts/3910/3</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 16:45:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21524</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>TTRPG&#39;s like &quot;Loot Grind&#39; Videogames?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>How about making loot relevant by binding skills (and spells) to gear? Each equipped item adds to skills or - in case of staves and jewelry - contributes to the available spell(s)? This way your loot is your build.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ttrpgs-like-loot-grind-videogames/3890/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 16:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21522</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Hard science fiction games</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@alanmfox]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I bough Diaspora a while back. It generally tries to be hard sci-fi, with the notable exception of interstellar travel as mentioned above. For what it’s worth, it’s got the atomic rockets seal of approval, which is where I learned about it:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.projectrho.com/public_html/rocket/sealofapproval.php" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.projectrho.com/public_html/rocket/sealofapproval.php</a></p>
<p>If you’re more or less system agnostic and are just looking for a good setting, Zozer Games, on drivethrurpg has a couple of settings/background references for a near-future hard-sci-fi game, sans interstellar travel</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/hard-science-fiction-games/3821/25</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 16:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21521</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>How do you play World of Dungeons?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@yochaigal]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>If I may be so bold… You should let <a class="mention" href="/u/tam">@Tam</a> manage it. She’s the best, and loves WoDu hacks.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-world-of-dungeons/1593/17</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 16:06:44 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21520</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>TTRPG&#39;s like &quot;Loot Grind&#39; Videogames?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I agree that abilities aren’t what make a looter a looter, but I do think the added combo possibilities make things more interesting in a team game. Without that, you’re mostly just trying to combine the pieces of gear into one set per player that works well and it doesn’t matter much who uses what. Different abilities also means that different pieces of gear can be more or less useful depending on your character setup.</p>
<p>But I should be clear that my sketched out proposal isn’t the only way to do this type of game as a TTRPG, just what would be my starting point. For example, I’ve pretty much dropped the inventory management aspect mostly because I personally find that a bit tedious.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ttrpgs-like-loot-grind-videogames/3890/21</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 15:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21518</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>TTRPG&#39;s like &quot;Loot Grind&#39; Videogames?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I think your setup is the closest to a working solution so far. Archetypes/builds are definitely an important part of looter genre and a lot of motivation behind looting is optimal gear acquisition for a given build. Great point! The only thing I’m not convinced is needed is skill tree. Original Diablo had no skill tree, each class had a single unique ability (and crap one at that: rogue could spot traps that weren’t real danger, warrior could repair weapons permanently decreasing its peak durability, mage could recharge staves permanently decreasing peek charge value) but it was, no, is a great game. <img src="/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>Diversity in Diablo 1 came from the differences in damage output, type of damage produced, character speed and preferred weapons. Magic was available to any character it’s just that inherent stat caps made mages more magical. The skill tree from Diablo 2 was transplanted over to Hellgate: London and didn’t work that well in this otherwise interesting MMO looter. So I don’t think that this is what makes looter a looter.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ttrpgs-like-loot-grind-videogames/3890/20</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 14:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21517</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Running a PbtA game versus a more traditional game?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@funkaoshi]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>This feels like a really succinct summary as well. Rolling introduces complications, which in a lot of PbtA games is what the players in the game (GM included) wants. With OSR games that complication is a chance for failure you are usually trying to avoid.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/running-a-pbta-game-versus-a-more-traditional-game/3842/34</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 14:04:25 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21516</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Running a PbtA game versus a more traditional game?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@V.Feasson]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I agree, I’d see rolling in a Pbta closer to a reward (oh my god something exciting is about to happen, weither I succeed or fail), whereas in OSR-like style it’s more like a necessary risk or even a punishment.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/running-a-pbta-game-versus-a-more-traditional-game/3842/33</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 12:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21515</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>RPGs that have audience involvement</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dannythewall]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Well, Matt Baume has run a few live shows of Dungeons and Drag Queens for his podcast Queens of Adventure, if that’s any inspiration.<br>
</p><div class="lazyYT" data-youtube-id="KdAi1OzbJ_s" data-youtube-title="Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons &amp;amp; Drag Queens on Queens of Adventure" data-width="480" data-height="270" data-parameters="feature=oembed&amp;wmode=opaque"></div> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/rpgs-that-have-audience-involvement/3869/17</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 12:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21514</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I heart World of Dungeons 1979 (let’s read them hacks &amp; drifts)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Bryan_Mullins]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p><em>First up, the hack document that got me all hype this morning and my response!</em></p>
<p><a class="mention" href="/u/tam">@Tam</a> talks about<br>
<a href="https://drive.google.com/open?id=1d5HphGYKjhDtFnPlEUKu-FcFJ88UlNnX" rel="nofollow noopener">this hack</a><br>
<a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-world-of-dungeons/1593/2">here</a>.</p>
<p><em>Here’s what I think:</em><br>
Tam</p>
<p>I just read through your WoDu hack, and I have to admit that I was startled to see the number of pages it totaled. I don’t know if I have any “notes” for you on it, but I do like it. The section on binding / summoning got me hype just reading it.</p>
<p>As a Hazard Die GM, I also fully support its addition and use here. I pretty much use Brendan’s systems whenever I can remember to. I think the Hazard Die is a nice, neat companion for the Die of Fate! I don’t think I’ve seen the Combat Hazard Die before but I now I want to try and use it. There are a number of things in your doc that I will be copying into my Little Game Book journal to remind me to bring some of these elements into play more often.</p>
<p>It’s very cool, and I will be borrowing from you. I’m envious of your layout and design elements…I just don’t have the chops or patience for nice looking drafts!</p>
<p>Here’s my reaction to seeing Hazard system mentioned:<br>
<img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/9/9c0da53244d0e0b73bd767bcc7c995f20074136b.gif" alt="image" data-base62-sha1="mgvIERhsOvFLjdtWwPrsKeeAUoX" width="480" height="322"></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-heart-world-of-dungeons-1979-let-s-read-them-hacks-drifts/3910/2</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21513</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>I heart World of Dungeons 1979 (let’s read them hacks &amp; drifts)</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Bryan_Mullins]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p><em>TL;DR:</em><br>
<em>Bryan reads, and talks about what he loves in the many WoDu Hacks that he comes across…as he finds them. Come join us to nerd-out.</em></p>
<p><em>What? WHY?</em><br>
Okay, so I’m not new here so much as I am a major lurker. I have admired the Gauntlet from afar since the G+ days, and eventually came here because members of the community like <a class="mention" href="/u/yochaigal">@yochaigal</a> have created a lot of great discussion around WoDu (World of Dungeons 1979), and DW (Dungeon World) … how to GM very light systems, how to Old School your non-D&amp;D games…all topics that are dear to my heart.</p>
<p>As I was reading, <a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/how-do-you-play-world-of-dungeons/">one of the many WoDu topics</a> i’ve bookmarked, I got super hype and started typing an enthusiastic response to one of the linked WoDu hack documents…at about the 2 paragraph mark I started to feel guilty…I felt like I was swinging way OT, and just nerding out about the design of the hack I’d just started reading…and now I’m here…starting a thread where I can just…read and respond to each WoDu I find as I come across it.</p>
<p>It’s like a “let’s read” and we can just be safe and lose our shit over how fun running hacking this game is.<br>
Welcome! Thanks for reading!</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/i-heart-world-of-dungeons-1979-let-s-read-them-hacks-drifts/3910/1</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 11:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21512</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>World of Dungeons &amp; hacks &amp; iterations</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Bryan_Mullins]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>FIXED!</p>
<p>Yes there must be. I’ll investigate what went wrong with the link.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/world-of-dungeons-hacks-iterations/87/29</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 10:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21511</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>What are you working on right now?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dannythewall]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Elevator Pitch?<br>
The city’s law enforcement system is upheld by two distinct yet equally important extremes.<br>
Those who hold to a no-nonsense, dedicated commitment to justice and social order.<br>
And … clowns.</p>
<p>I recently found some stuff that I worked on when I was once was pitching animated series ideas to Cartoon Network WAAAYYY back in the day. I figured I might as well try to make it a quick one-page RPG.</p>
<p>So, behold: Good Cop, Clown Cop.</p>
<p>It’s just version 1.0, but I’ll try to playtest it in a session next month. If anyone wants to playtest feel free to have a read-through. You can find on my website at <a href="https://wheresdannywall.wixsite.com/home/role-playing-games" rel="nofollow noopener">https://wheresdannywall.wixsite.com/home/role-playing-games</a><br>
Or, at the very least, it was a nice palette cleanser from some of the other projects I’ve been working on.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/what-are-you-working-on-right-now/1322/135</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 08:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21510</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>World of Dungeons &amp; hacks &amp; iterations</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@_ry]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Is there an issue with that link? I just saw a blank page with the words “World of Dungeons”</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/world-of-dungeons-hacks-iterations/87/28</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 05:53:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21507</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Kormoran&#39;s Wheel</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@signalstation]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Should your purse come up short when a pretty bauble has caught your eye, or should a bout of haggling leave you dejected while some counter-polisher laughs at your besting, you may hear a soft voice offer to make the purchase on your behalf. Worry not. There’s no shop keep who’d let you accept this offer, even if you were tempted. Pelleck the Coin Bearer knows what they did, and why that coin is theirs forever. That coin, and none other.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-kormorans-wheel/3672/15</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 01:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21500</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Trophy: Barsul Prison</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@signalstation]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>An infrequently used path to shortening one’s sentence is to agree to serve as a sorrow-horse for one of Ambaret’s perfumed and puffed up thespians. A few actors a year offer the warden “donations” in exchange for time with a prisoner, hoping to learn to ape the prisoner’s slumped and dejected carriage, begging them to dwell on their deepest sorrows so they may mirror the prisoner’s genuine despair when next they appear on stage.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/trophy-barsul-prison/2793/22</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:47:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21499</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>TTRPG&#39;s like &quot;Loot Grind&#39; Videogames?</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Anders]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Interesting topic! I have some thoughts which I hope I can formulate reasonably coherently despite this being well past midnight and I’m only up because sleep eludes me.</p>
<p>I’ve played quite a lot of this style of game, mainly Diablo 2 and 3 (and some imitators like Torchlight) and Borderlands 1 and 2 (the Pre-Sequel had some annoying areas so I haven’t played that as much).</p>
<p>For me, the fun of the loot aspect of these games is that it encourages mixing up your playing style, a feature that was noted upthread. In Borderlands, trying out a weapon that seems interesting and realizing that that specific combination of characteristics makes it hilariously fun in some siutations and useless in others is a big part of the draw, and finding something in Diablo 3 that enables a completely new build is also interesting.</p>
<p>As a sidenote, many, if not most, MMORPGs have at least some of this even if the emphasis is less on the randomized items in my experience, and for me personally they do it in a much less interesting way where you’re mainly comparing minor bonuses and trying to decide which is slightly more advantageous. That’s even less interesting in a TTRPG, I think, so I’m going to put that up as something to avoid.</p>
<p>Another attraction, as was also mentioned upthread, is the ability to zone out a bit while you’re playing. When I play these games I’m a bit more engaged than when I do extended mining sessions in Minecraft, but not all that much. However, I don’t think this is something we need to emulate in a TTRPG as I think that’s a pleasure specific to the solitary video game experience.</p>
<p>Something I think you do want is the fast and furious pace of combat. You don’t want a system where a typical fight takes up most of a session so that a player who chose to go with an unorthodox equipment combination will have a bad time for that whole time. You want combat to be about mowing down hordes of mooks with the occasional tougher enemy that takes a few hits to take down, and some very rare fights against boss type monsters that shake things up. You want a typical fight to be against 20+ enemies rather than a more typical 3-10, but most of those enemies should die on a single hit.</p>
<p>I think you also want the characters to have enough abilities that interact with the item abilities to make some items clearly better for some characters, or at least clearly different. For example, if one character has an ability that makes lightning attacks chain to additional enemies and another character has an ability that increases the range of lightning attacks, who has more use for the short-range lightning bolt thrower? Is it more useful to kill more enemies close-up or to be able to pick off more dangerous ones at range?</p>
<p>Another thing to take into consideration is that even with a fairly simple combat system, a TTRPG will never be able to match the pace of a computer game. On the other hand, with a TTRPG you will (hopefully) not be playing through the same story over and over and over again until it becomes more of a nuisance because it stops you from getting straight to the fight-loot-equip loop so there’s a much greater potential for the consequences of the fight to be interesting.</p>
<p>It was also noted upthread that there are boardgames that do this style of game quite well, like Descent, Zombicide, and Shadows of Brimstone. Rather than that being an argument against making this type of TTRPG, I think those are examples to learn from when making this type of TTRPG, especially when it comes to combat rules.</p>
<p>One inspiration that can be taken from them, which I think was also mentioned, is the use of cards. Used correctly, I think cards could be used to both make the items feel more substantial and simplify the loot division process. I think you probably want to use card combinations rather than have each item be a single card, if only to retain that sense of RNG created loot.</p>
<p>To sketch out my ideas for a combat system very stream-of-consciously (bullet-pointed after the fact because it turned into one long-ass rambling paragraph):</p>
<ul>
<li>I would start by using zones to simplify range calculations and terrain effects.</li>
<li>There would be no numbers treadmill - player hit points will go up, but their offensive capabilities will be based around how many enemies they can take out and how powerful effects they can create rather than damage numbers.</li>
<li>Similarly, enemies will be on a simple scale of something like minion (one hit point), grunt (two hit points), lieutenant (enough hp that it takes one character two turns to take them down, so maybe five?), and boss (enough hp that if the whole party goes all out on them it takes at least three turns to take them down).</li>
<li>Character classes/playbooks should be clear archetypes with fairly free advancement to enable different builds for replayability, so ability pools rather than trees, with the power coming from synergies between abilities and between abilities and equipment.</li>
<li>Equipment should be fairly limited, like armor, a couple of weapons, and one or two utility items. (The ability to have more equipment could also be part of increasing in power.)</li>
<li>Items would be generated through card draws, with one card for the base item, up to maybe two or three for positive abilities, and sometimes a drawback.</li>
<li>Most characters should be able to use most items, with effectiveness for a particular character being determined more by build and synergies rather than class.</li>
<li>Players should make at most one die roll during their turn (though that could involve a couple of dice), and no rolls outside their turn.</li>
<li>Enemies probably shouldn’t roll at all so player characters deploy defenses on their own turn.</li>
<li>Most characters should probably have some kind of resource management system to keep their turns from being to samey and to add some more texture to the rules. This could be long-term (stretching over multiple combat) and/or short-term (from turn to turn).</li>
<li>Enemies should generally be fairly predictable to avoid the players doing a lot of second-guessing and trying to figure out what possibilities they need to prepare for.</li>
<li>A campaign should have a finite, fairly short, length. I think I would aim for three to five sessions, with two or three quick combats per session depending on how much else is going on, and an apetizer followed by a single epic boss battle for the last one. (Or perhaps two boss battles, so you can get some epic loot from the first to use in the second?)</li>
</ul>
<p>Whew, that got a lot longer than I had thought. Time to go back to bed now.</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ttrpgs-like-loot-grind-videogames/3890/19</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2019 00:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21497</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Seeking Feedback - Hesitation at the Gate</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Radmad]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>the aim for that chapter is to encourage the entire playgroup to collaborate on what kind of world and thus what kind of stories they want to tell. A more explicit “please play session 0” if you will. I see how that’s confusing if it placed before the character creation section, since a reader is going to focusing on what <em>they personally</em> are creating at that point. I agree that putting that after chargen will help with readability, that will create a better segue as the new flow would be personal chargen -&gt; players<br>
's order -&gt; entire group’s world</p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/seeking-feedback-hesitation-at-the-gate/3805/11</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 23:55:14 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21496</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Seeking Feedback - Hesitation at the Gate</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@dominik]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>I don’t know if this is useful and I haven’t thought about this a lot yet but there are two major differences between social and magical here. One is that unlike magical, social questions are open and there is no rigid structure here to work with. But another is that a lot of social is either/or: is nobility hedonistic or conservative? is middle class skillful or shady? At the same time magical is presented as (as far as I understand at least) "everything is out there, just pick your focus.</p>
<p>What if players were to exclude certain supernatural aspects from their chronicle? Each could potentially be very different in terms of ambience, but I don’t really know if this would work in practice. This could either focus each game or completely derail what this game is about. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/confused.png?v=9" title=":confused:" class="emoji" alt=":confused:"></p> ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/seeking-feedback-hesitation-at-the-gate/3805/10</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 23:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21495</guid>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>World of Dungeons &amp; hacks &amp; iterations</title>
        <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Bryan_Mullins]]></dc:creator>
        <description><![CDATA[ <p>Looking forward to perusing this!</p>
<p>Here’s the version of WoDu I use, a slight remix in a playbook format. I also often use <em>Wonder &amp; Wickedness</em> as a drop-in “Vancian” magic system when players ask for that sort of thing.</p>
<aside class="onebox googledrive">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1AzHe5IUvyUmcPohOos2ngBod81DX4us2/view?usp=drivesdk" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">drive.google.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    
<div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/362;"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/5/534a50d56619d01c82eec64d84cd9a47dab87b57.png" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1AzHe5IUvyUmcPohOos2ngBod81DX4us2/view?usp=drivesdk" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">WODHACK.pdf</a></h3>

<p>Google Drive file.</p>

  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>
 ]]></description>
        <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/world-of-dungeons-hacks-iterations/87/27</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 22:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
        <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-post-21485</guid>
      </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
