<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:discourse="http://www.discourse.org/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hype - The Gauntlet Forums</title>
    <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/c/hype</link>
    <description>Topics in the &#39;Hype&#39; category For discussions of Kickstarters, Patreons, Conventions, etc. (No looking for players posts. See posting guidelines below…)</description>
    
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 19:55:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/c/hype.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
          <title>New MexiCon 2020 Kickstarter</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Bohnhoff]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/bohnhoff">@Bohnhoff</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>New MexiCon is a small RPG convention in Albuquerque, New Mexico. We focus exclusively on indie and small press games, the kinds of things that don’t receive much attention at other venues.</p>
<p>We just launched the kickstarter to pre-sell badges. If you’re interested in these kinds of games and are in the southwest US, I hope you give it a look and consider joining us in April!</p>
<p>We have backing tiers for a badge, a badge and a hotel room, and just a support tier if you can’t attend but want to help us out.</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1469878195/new-mexicon-2020" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Kickstarter</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/388;"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/5/5fff2c57b241546dd5c2818d58cdd987916806d7.jpeg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1469878195/new-mexicon-2020" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">New MexiCon 2020</a></h3>

<p>This is the 7th annual New MexiCon indie roleplaying convention! #RecognizeKSRU</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/new-mexicon-2020-kickstarter/3889">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/new-mexicon-2020-kickstarter/3889</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 19:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3889</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/new-mexicon-2020-kickstarter/3889.rss">New MexiCon 2020 Kickstarter</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Ask the Oracle - Official Podcast for the Ironsworn RPG</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@ShawnTomkin]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/shawntomkin">@ShawnTomkin</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve started putting out a weekly podcast dedicated to my free small press RPG. The first two episodes, available now, are dedicated to world creation and character creation for the two-player, GM-less campaign which we’ll undertake in future episodes.</p>
<p>Available at <a href="https://ironsworn.podbean.com/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://ironsworn.podbean.com/</a>, and (hopefully) on your preferred podcast app.</p>
<p>Mad respect to all of the Gauntlet podcasters. Holy cow, is it a bunch of work.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ask-the-oracle-official-podcast-for-the-ironsworn-rpg/3859">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ask-the-oracle-official-podcast-for-the-ironsworn-rpg/3859</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 04:01:23 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3859</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/ask-the-oracle-official-podcast-for-the-ironsworn-rpg/3859.rss">Ask the Oracle - Official Podcast for the Ironsworn RPG</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Rusałka is Now Available</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Nick Wedig’s game Rusałka is super great and I love it: <a href="https://nickwedig.itch.io/rusalka" rel="nofollow noopener">https://nickwedig.itch.io/rusalka</a> (If you want to buy it as a deck of cards, it is also available on DTRPG: <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/273096/Rusalka" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/273096/Rusalka</a>). This is a very focused monkey’s paw of a game - you will play people who really need things, and you will also play the cruel supernatural monsters who will give them precisely what they ask for.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/rusalka-is-now-available/3856">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/rusalka-is-now-available/3856</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 22:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3856</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/rusalka-is-now-available/3856.rss">Rusałka is Now Available</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Crowdfunding Collection #123</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I present to you the <b><a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/11/03/crowdfunding-collection-123/" rel="nofollow noopener">new Crowdfunding Collection #123, including every tabletop rpg project started between 10/30 and 11/03</a></b>.</p>
<p>Despite the last collection been just 4 days ago, you’ll find that there are 22 projects included in this. As for the next, it might get delayed for three weeks, or a bit more, since I will take a trip to The Night in Question – which effectively will take two weekends as I’ll again take a small US vacation.</p>
<p>First of all, I’d like to direct your attention towards the German translation of <b>Lovecraftesque</b>. If you like to support the game line abroad, if you do speak German, take a look. The publisher is new, I do think reliable, and needs some more support.<br>
In regards of English language projects, there’s the <b>Dark V01D Science Fiction</b> ttrpg. A project from Germany that is presented and offered in English. The SF setting is visibly inspired by the 80s and the system developed of from The Dark Eye. Though the creator chose a more narrative approach with just keeping the combat practical. It should be worth having a look. Then there is <b>Mystic Lilies</b>, a card based game, which focussed on the dramatic conflict among witches and dark arts. The author referes Monsterhearts, Touhou Project, Bayonetta and Madoka Magica as points of references. While I don’t consider Bayonetta as dramatic – imho it’s more like „Fucking stylish, in your FACE Fucker! BOW BOW BOW“-drama than eny of the other – I find my self really intruiged by the concept presented and recommend having a look. Then there’s <b>Moonpunk</b>, a PbtA game, in which you play different kinds of punks rebelling on the moon. The game comes in the form of a punk-zine and does look interesting.<br>
Then there are two Larps, <b>Hi-Ho!</b> aims to offers a fun single-player Larp. Though going by the video it can be played with oneself and a quite literal socketpuppet. A nice, rather inexpensive, idea that might be worth having a look at. <b>System 7</b> offers a sytem, from the looks card based, for Larps and ttrpgs, with the opportunity to simulate any genre from fantasy to vampires. Which does make it interesting.<br>
Then you’ll find <b>Leopard Women of Venus</b> for DCC among the settings. As the name indicates it revels in a Golden Age comic book approach and has women riding through space on dragon-crocodiles while shooting fire/lasers from their helmets. Which lookes like ridiculously absurd fun. Just take a look. I personally, for now, pledged for the <b>Super Blood Harvest</b> adventure. It’s a collection of actually three modules, I guess setting up on a supposed OSR rule set, yet very stylish and with vampires. Well, and if I had a 3D printer I might have pledged for the very cool looking <b>Draconic Dice Crypts</b> STL files.<br>
There are many more interesting, cool and fun projects, just take a look:</p>
<p><b>English Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>3 Role-Playing Games<br>
2 Larps<br>
1 Setting<br>
1 Sourcebook<br>
4 Adventures<br>
1 Dice Project<br>
2 Dice Accessoires<br>
1 Maps &amp; Tokens Project<br>
1 Enamel Pin<br>
2 Various RPG Projects</p>
<p><b>German Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Role-Playing Game<br>
1 Sourcebook</p>
<p><b>Spanish Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Sourcebook</p>
<p><b>French Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Role-Playing Game</p>
<p>Article: <a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/11/03/crowdfunding-collection-123/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://teylen.blog/2019/11/03/crowdfunding-collection-123/</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-123/3854">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-123/3854</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 16:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3854</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-123/3854.rss">Crowdfunding Collection #123</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Crowdfunding Collection #122, including every tabletop rpg project started between 10/13 and 10/30</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I present to you the <b><a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/10/30/crowdfunding-collection-122/" rel="nofollow noopener">new Crowdfunding Collection #122, including every tabletop rpg project started between 10/13 and 10/30.</a></b></p>
<p>Following quite a break, as I enjoyed PDXcon and SPIEL, I am back at an unusual weekday. The collection covers 17 days, which has seen quite some projects started and other closed. For 7 projects I’ve been to late, you’ll find them at the end of this post. Thus, to lose no more, let’s start.</p>
<p><b>Voidheart</b> is essentially a Urban Fantasy game. You play mundane human beings who discover that there is more to the world than they knew and have to fight back against a variety of creatures. Jay Iles describe it as being about a psychic rebellion and compares it to works like Psychonauts, Persona 5 and Inception. The PbtA games overs a quickstart and I suggest you take a look. <b>The Ruin</b> has a quickstart as well. Though it’s rather based on D&amp;D 5E and offers a post-apocalyptic setting to explore and survive. I do quite like the illustrations. Which is as well a cool aspect of <b>Renascentia</b>. The originally Italian game takes the peninsula as a setting and enriches it with magic and enchantments apparently set in what I would call „somewhat medieval to renaissance“ times. With <b>Arcana Academy</b> you’ll find a PbtA game that aims to over the experience of attending Hogwarts (Harry Potter) or Brakebills (Magicians), apparently taking a lighter take on the latter.<br>
If you are yearning for Fantasy, take a look at <b>Era: Lost Legend</b>. The game is the newest addition to the Era-system family and aims to provide a Final Fantasy style gaming experience; take a look. <b>Against the Darkmaster</b> does offer classical fantasy sagas and by it’s own claims „heavy metal combat“. Which it does provide by a simple d100 system and the illustration, save from the opulent thumbnail, look OSR-style to me. If you prefer your fantasy D&amp;D 5E style, just take a look at <b>The Dark Forest</b>.<br>
If you are looking for an interesting take on survival horror, take a look at <b>Survival of the Able</b>. You’ll be playing people with disabilities during the medieval times in western Europe and next to the normal ailments of the era there are zombies too! It does use a custom tailored version of fudge as its system. While I likely won’t back it, it’s an interesting idea and I recommend having a look. You’ll find another horror RPG in <b>All is Madness</b>. The characters have to confront their fears or die. While the project doesn’t say a lot about it’s system, $10 isn’t that expensive and it might be worth having a look – a rather quick one as it has only hours left on its clock.<br>
If you prefer Science Fiction, you might like to check out <b>Space Kings</b>. The card based game invites improvisation to have your characters and crews stand up to the government. <b>Spaced</b> does offer a more classic approach with a d100 system and its developers experience Delve. You’ll be crashing with your space ship and got to explore your crash site. If you like detailed, original settings, check out <b>Swords and Spaceships</b>. The project doesn’t talk that much about the system, but looks nice and talks a lot about its setting.<br>
Western are basically Science Fiction in historical, at least some SF. With <b>Devil’s Staircase</b> you can take your dusty cowboy boots on and engage in the wild west. It is a diceless rules-light game and the InDemand phase will only last for like 2 more days. If you like your West with Elves, Orcs and other fantasy creatures, check out <b>Gaval Tales</b>. It has them all and uses d8 and d12 at least.<br>
If you fancy game books, you’ll find a quite traditional one with <b>The Necronomicon Gamebook – Carcosa</b>. <b>Pitch Black</b> is more unconventional, by basically being an audio based gamebook. Well, and <b>Spire’s End</b> does approach the gamebook theme with cards. Plus it is the one that tempts me most.<br>
Matt Colvilles sourcebook <b>Kingdoms, Warfare &amp; More Minis!</b> got me to actually back it, as I like the topic and are curious about his take. There are, of course, many more very interesting, cool projects, just check the collection:</p>
<p><b>English Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>4 Role-Playing Games<br>
3 Fantasy Role-Playing Games<br>
2 Horror Role-Playing Games<br>
3 Science Fiction Role-Playing Games<br>
2 Wild West Role-Playing Games<br>
1 Gamebook<br>
1 Audio-Gamebook<br>
1 Card-Gamebook<br>
2 Settings<br>
3 Magazines<br>
3 Sourcebooks<br>
6 D&amp;D 5E Sourcebooks<br>
3 Adventures<br>
5 D&amp;D 5E Adventures<br>
3 Dice Projects<br>
1 Dice Coin<br>
4 Accessoires<br>
1 Deck of Cards<br>
1 App<br>
2 Enamel Pins<br>
2 Maps &amp; Tokens<br>
2 Various RPG Projects</p>
<p><b>German Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Sourcebook</p>
<p><b>Spanish Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Role-Playing Game<br>
1 Sourcebook<br>
1 Adventure</p>
<p><b>French Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>4 Role-Playing Games<br>
3 Dark Fantasy Role-Playing Games<br>
1 Sourcebook</p>
<p><b>Started and already Done</b></p>
<p>7 Projects</p>
<p>Article: <a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/10/30/crowdfunding-collection-122/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://teylen.blog/2019/10/30/crowdfunding-collection-122/</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-122-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-10-13-and-10-30/3822">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-122-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-10-13-and-10-30/3822</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 16:45:51 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3822</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-122-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-10-13-and-10-30/3822.rss">Crowdfunding Collection #122, including every tabletop rpg project started between 10/13 and 10/30</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Gauntlet Merch?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@chrisshorb]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/chrisshorb">@chrisshorb</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Does anyone know if there’s any Gauntlet Merch? My midlife crisis is realizing I have never had enough nerdy shirts. Woe is me, I only own 2 DW t-shirts in the nerdish category (unless Iron Maiden or David Bowie shirts count as nerdish).</p>
<p>So, to the point - any Gauntlet tshirts? I would buy at least one.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 6</p>
            <p>Participants: 4</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-merch/3818">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-merch/3818</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2019 04:13:17 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3818</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/gauntlet-merch/3818.rss">Gauntlet Merch?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>VIDEOSTORE - A Monster of the Week double feature</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@SinisterBeard]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/sinisterbeard">@SinisterBeard</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Hey all! My newest release, VIDEOSTORE has just gone live. It’s two deluxe mysteries for Monster of the Week, including an expanded version of Gauntlet Hangouts favourite All Are Punished. If you like MOTW, 80s horror, and making fun of tech bros and incels, check it out!</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/292991/VIDEOSTORE--A-Monster-of-the-Week-Double-Feature/../../../themes/dtrpg/favicon.ico" class="site-icon" width="16" height="16">
      <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/292991/VIDEOSTORE--A-Monster-of-the-Week-Double-Feature" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">drivethrurpg.com</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:386/500;"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/a/ab1e372fe04786a497ac8ef37003439bea363c0b.jpeg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/292991/VIDEOSTORE--A-Monster-of-the-Week-Double-Feature" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">VIDEOSTORE - A Monster of the Week Double Feature - Sinister Beard Games |...</a></h3>

<p>Head back to the video libraries of the decade that taste forgot in these two thrilling, ghoulish Monster of the Week my</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

<p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/4/4c748e13affda3820d2e26011df70c2660f5177e.jpeg" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/aUm0lLTDvWQwThmUnqwpNsUzZg2.jpeg?dl=1" title="Cover - Itchio.jpg" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/4/4c748e13affda3820d2e26011df70c2660f5177e_2_595x500.jpeg" alt="Cover%20-%20Itchio" data-base62-sha1="aUm0lLTDvWQwThmUnqwpNsUzZg2" width="595" height="500" srcset="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/4/4c748e13affda3820d2e26011df70c2660f5177e_2_595x500.jpeg, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/4/4c748e13affda3820d2e26011df70c2660f5177e_2_892x750.jpeg 1.5x, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/4/4c748e13affda3820d2e26011df70c2660f5177e_2_1190x1000.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/4/4c748e13affda3820d2e26011df70c2660f5177e_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">Cover - Itchio.jpg</span><span class="informations">1913×1606 1.22 MB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 2</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/videostore-a-monster-of-the-week-double-feature/3806">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/videostore-a-monster-of-the-week-double-feature/3806</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3806</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/videostore-a-monster-of-the-week-double-feature/3806.rss">VIDEOSTORE - A Monster of the Week double feature</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Chuck Tingle, The Tingleverse Episode - Full Metal RPG</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@CarrionCallingCard]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/carrioncallingcard">@CarrionCallingCard</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Hello Everyone,</p>
<p>My name is Brendan and I host a roleplaying game discussion podcast called Full Metal RPG.</p>
<p>I love to follow the work of Chuck Tingle, and so when he released “The Tingleverse” RPG I was an early adopter. My friend Richard who is also a member of the Gauntlet community and co-host of the show encouraged me to reach out to Chuck and invite him on the show to talk about the game.</p>
<p>I did just that, and I’m so happy how it turned out! I guess that’s the power of asking! Chuck came on and talked about the game and how Love is Real. I hope that you will take a second and listen to the episode, I have it linked for you below. Thanks for reading!</p>
<p><iframe width="100%" height="166" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?visual=false&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fapi.soundcloud.com%2Ftracks%2F702731542&amp;show_artwork=true&amp;maxheight=166" seamless="seamless" sandbox="allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-forms allow-popups allow-popups-to-escape-sandbox allow-presentation"></iframe></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 5</p>
            <p>Participants: 4</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/chuck-tingle-the-tingleverse-episode-full-metal-rpg/3802">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/chuck-tingle-the-tingleverse-episode-full-metal-rpg/3802</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 17:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3802</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/chuck-tingle-the-tingleverse-episode-full-metal-rpg/3802.rss">Chuck Tingle, The Tingleverse Episode - Full Metal RPG</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>You are invited to Gamicon 2020</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@DavidMK]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/davidmk">@DavidMK</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>By the way, you are all invited to attend Gamicon 2020 in Cedar Rapids, IA, Feb. 28-March 1. I’m part of a sub-group called Corridor Games on Demand that features small press and indie games at the convention. If you’d like more information, please message me here or email me at <a href="mailto:dmkcreative@gmail.com">dmkcreative@gmail.com</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 3</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/you-are-invited-to-gamicon-2020/3777">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/you-are-invited-to-gamicon-2020/3777</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 13:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3777</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/you-are-invited-to-gamicon-2020/3777.rss">You are invited to Gamicon 2020</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The Big Book of Amazing Tales is on Kickstarter</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@MrLloyd]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/mrlloyd">@MrLloyd</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>The <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/amazingtales/the-big-book-of-amazing-tales" rel="nofollow noopener">Big Book of Amazing Tales</a> is a collection of adventures for Amazing Tales, the RPG for kids aged four and up to play together with their parents. It will also include a chapter by game designer and teacher Baz Stevens on using RPGs in the classroom, and a piece by child therapist Lilly Smith on using RPGs to support kids with additional needs.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/amazingtales/the-big-book-of-amazing-tales" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/2/2dfdc558c58f81206e442ef75f5e213b5690150a.png" alt="website%20banner" data-base62-sha1="6yRbDQxK51bxgRL9tzh4iIV2cKS" width="690" height="266"></a></p>
<p>What are the adventures?</p>
<ul>
<li>
<strong>The Quest for the Dragon Crown -</strong>  this campaign complements the Magical Kingdom’s setting. The heroes take on an epic quest to save the kingdom of Merrydown from invading dragons. It’s got ghosts, mermaids, sea monsters, magical forests and a whole lot of dragons.</li>
<li>
<strong>Captain Cadava’s Treasure</strong>  - is a campaign for the Pirate Seas setting. A coded treasure map leads the heroes to a long lost treasure. But the heroes aren’t the only ones looking for it, and Captain Cadava might not be quite as dead as people think!</li>
<li>
<strong>The Cryptid Conundrum</strong>  - uses the Adventures Among the Stars setting. Important Space Rangers and Scientists have been kidnapped by the Cryptids, an alien race obsessed with secret codes and puzzles. The heroes must travel to different planets to investigte and unlock the secrets of the Cryptids if they are to foil their plans.</li>
<li>
<strong>A Dream of Trees</strong>  - the wisest animals know that fairy land exists in the dreams of trees. So when things start to go wrong in fairy land might the problems be found with the trees themselves? The heroes will need their wits, and knowledge of the natural world to solve the problems.</li>
</ul>
<p>And if you haven’t got Amazing Tales don’t worry. You can add the core book to your pledge.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/amazingtales/the-big-book-of-amazing-tales" rel="nofollow noopener">Check it out!</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 5</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-big-book-of-amazing-tales-is-on-kickstarter/3729">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-big-book-of-amazing-tales-is-on-kickstarter/3729</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 07:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3729</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-big-book-of-amazing-tales-is-on-kickstarter/3729.rss">The Big Book of Amazing Tales is on Kickstarter</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Survival of the Able Now Infecting Kickstarter</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jacob_Wood]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jacob_wood">@Jacob_Wood</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/4/4688049b741da8242bc0e86c4dfff9bdaa6418f2.png" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/a3WQ5wkHMTDpXg7jKco4jdfEqUG.png?dl=1" title="SotA Promo.png" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/4/4688049b741da8242bc0e86c4dfff9bdaa6418f2_2_690x388.png" alt="SotA%20Promo" data-base62-sha1="a3WQ5wkHMTDpXg7jKco4jdfEqUG" width="690" height="388" srcset="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/4/4688049b741da8242bc0e86c4dfff9bdaa6418f2_2_690x388.png, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/4/4688049b741da8242bc0e86c4dfff9bdaa6418f2.png 1.5x, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/4/4688049b741da8242bc0e86c4dfff9bdaa6418f2.png 2x" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/4/4688049b741da8242bc0e86c4dfff9bdaa6418f2_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">SotA Promo.png</span><span class="informations">1024×576 648 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div></p>
<p>The Black Death has come to your village. Everywhere around you people are succumbing to the plague. Quarantines are doing little to stem the tide of decay that is coming your way. Worst of all, you and the others in your almshouse have been left to fend for yourselves.</p>
<p>Oh, and did we mention plague victims are rising as zombies?</p>
<p>In Survival of the Able you’re a person with a disability living in a European almshouse when the Black Death arrives. Little is known about where the plague originated or how to stop it, but those who die from it are rising again—and they’re hungry for flesh. Since everyone else has succumbed to the plague, it’s up to a handful of you to make your way out of town and away to safety. You may not be the biggest, the strongest, or the fittest, but you’re determined to survive.</p>
<h2>What is Survival of the Able?</h2>
<p>Survival of the Able is a tabletop RPG about empathy. In this game, you will play as a person with a disability in the Middle Ages. The world isn’t very hospitable to you and your kind, and that’s before plague-ridden zombies started rising up to devour everyone around them. As you struggle for survival, you’ll get a feeling for what it is like to endure discrimination, to struggle with inaccessible surroundings, and to overcome adversity. This isn’t a game about heroic people and their heroic deeds. It’s a game about ordinary folks who have no choice but to challenge the stereotypes that keep them down. It’s a game about overcoming 14th Century plagues and 21st Century discrimination.</p>
<h2>About the Campaign</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.accessiblegames.biz" rel="nofollow noopener">Accessible Games</a> is raising $8,000 in 30 days to fund production for the book. The game is already written, but it needs art, editing, and layout to be complete. You can contribute to get a PDF, a printed book, a custom illustration, or an online game with the game’s designer.</p>
<p>Survival of the Able was developed by Jacob Wood, a blind game designer, and is being produced by other disabled and marginalized contributors.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bit.ly/SotALive" rel="nofollow noopener">Scramble over to the Kickstarter campaign to get your copy today.</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 4</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/survival-of-the-able-now-infecting-kickstarter/3719">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/survival-of-the-able-now-infecting-kickstarter/3719</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 13:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3719</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/survival-of-the-able-now-infecting-kickstarter/3719.rss">Survival of the Able Now Infecting Kickstarter</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Arcana Academy - PbtA Game Inspired By Harry Potter Now On Kickstarter</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@TabletopDuck]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/tabletopduck">@TabletopDuck</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><div class="lightbox-wrapper"><a class="lightbox" href="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/e/e2114129c67921add1f096f615ad8e37ac2ef3bf.jpeg" data-download-href="/uploads/short-url/wfSSjnUE90XRGvLt5dgLfbg3qHB.jpeg?dl=1" title="mockup_final.jpg" rel="nofollow noopener"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/e/e2114129c67921add1f096f615ad8e37ac2ef3bf_2_396x500.jpeg" alt="mockup_final" data-base62-sha1="wfSSjnUE90XRGvLt5dgLfbg3qHB" width="396" height="500" srcset="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/e/e2114129c67921add1f096f615ad8e37ac2ef3bf_2_396x500.jpeg, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/e/e2114129c67921add1f096f615ad8e37ac2ef3bf_2_594x750.jpeg 1.5x, //gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/e/e2114129c67921add1f096f615ad8e37ac2ef3bf_2_792x1000.jpeg 2x" data-small-upload="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/optimized/2X/e/e2114129c67921add1f096f615ad8e37ac2ef3bf_2_10x10.png"><div class="meta">
<svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-far-image svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#far-image"></use></svg><span class="filename">mockup_final.jpg</span><span class="informations">1834×2311 966 KB</span><svg class="fa d-icon d-icon-discourse-expand svg-icon" aria-hidden="true"><use xlink:href="#discourse-expand"></use></svg>
</div></a></div><br>
Heya everyone, wanted to take some time to share my latest game that’s up on Kickstarter. Arcana Academy is a magic school RPG inspired by works like Harry Potter or The Magicians. We also took a lot of inspiration from City of Mist, Monsterhearts, and Masks to help us design the game.</p>
<p>We focused pretty heavily on mystery solving, freeform spell creation, and mechanics that mimic the way relationships change and evolve in these kinds of books/movies/shows. We recently launched on Kickstarter and quickly funded within 24 hours, but we’re still looking to spread some awareness.</p>
<p>If you like Powered by the Apocalypse games or magic schools as a setting, <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/tabletopcrow/arcana-academy" rel="nofollow noopener">check out our Kickstarter!</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 2</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/arcana-academy-pbta-game-inspired-by-harry-potter-now-on-kickstarter/3698">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/arcana-academy-pbta-game-inspired-by-harry-potter-now-on-kickstarter/3698</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 17:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3698</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/arcana-academy-pbta-game-inspired-by-harry-potter-now-on-kickstarter/3698.rss">Arcana Academy - PbtA Game Inspired By Harry Potter Now On Kickstarter</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>The Tannhauser Investment: A Mission for The Sprawl RPG</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@whodo]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/whodo">@whodo</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I’ve just released a new mission for The Sprawl RPG by Ardens Ludere and wanted to share it with everybody here as I know there are many PbtA enthusiasts within the community. This mission is the first of a trilogy that should be ready mid-late November so I’m releasing it as a free preview and would really love any feedback. It’s the first product I’ve put out for a PbtA game, between the different system and wanting to improve my layout skills it has provided a really engaging challenge.</p>
<p>The trilogy is called The Synth Convergence and the missions are thematically tied together by Synthetic Intelligence - AIs that are pushing their presence into the physical world, with their existence and presence being exploited by the already omnipresent Corporations. This mission, The Tannhauser Investment, sees the team contracted to undertake a hostile takeover of a Corporate subsidary by infiltrating a super-luxury hotel in order to force the majority shareholder into transfering their shares to an off-shore shell company. All in a days work for a professional, in and out with no collatoral damage.</p>
<p>You can download the mission for free from <a href="https://lunarshadow.itch.io/synth-convergence" rel="nofollow noopener">itch</a> or <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/291597/The-Tannhauser-Investment?affiliate_id=174853" rel="nofollow noopener">drivethruRPG</a> and I am extremely open to any and all feedback.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-tannhauser-investment-a-mission-for-the-sprawl-rpg/3694">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-tannhauser-investment-a-mission-for-the-sprawl-rpg/3694</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 12:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3694</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/the-tannhauser-investment-a-mission-for-the-sprawl-rpg/3694.rss">The Tannhauser Investment: A Mission for The Sprawl RPG</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Crowdfunding Collection #121, including every tabletop rpg project started between 10/07 and 10/13</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I present to you the <a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/10/13/crowdfunding-collection-121/" rel="nofollow noopener"><b>new Crowdfunding Collection #121, including every tabletop rpg project started between 10/07 and 10/13</b></a>.</p>
<p>This week I discovered and am very enthusiastic about <b>Moth Children, A Vampire TTRPG</b> created by Dane Asmund. I am really intruiged by the idea to combine moth, and their mythological background, with the creation and existence of vampires and thus genuinely curious with and fascinated by the setting.  It’s, at least for me, a excitingly novel approach to vampires and addition to the genre. The mechanics is based on two wheels – one the ST have and one each player has – which I consider interesting. The playtest of the game offers insight in what it will become and I trust the creator based on previous projects. I do highly recommend that you take a look at the project and back it.<br>
Another project I backed and recommend is <b>Doikayt: A Jewish TTRPG Anthology</b>. It offers a collection of short tabletop roleplaying games about Judaism or Jewish themes, written and illustrated by Jews. From what I’ve seen currently the anthology includes about ten games offering quite a variety in topic. I do recommend that you take a look and backed it myself as it ready very enticing.<br>
If you are more interested in historical fantasy, you should take a look at <b>Wolves of God</b>. The game uses England during the Dark Ages setting and the system of Stars without Numbers for the game mechanics, being quite close to B/X.<br>
For more fantasy you might take a look at <b>Advanced Fantasy</b>, a d100 based system that has been created with love for complex and challenging games in mind. Then there’s <b>Warden’s Game</b>. The project does offer rather little information in regards to setting or system yet appears to be a labour of love.<br>
The gamebook in this collection <b>Destiny Dez, Drum of Destiny</b>, is being created with very young children in mind, and offers an entry to role-playing games.<br>
Then, if your interested in Larps, you might like to try <b>Twain</b>. A small larp for one player. Which I find a quite curious concept.<br>
There are other quite interesting projects, like the <b>Fantasy World Creator</b>, which allows to easily create maps and tiles for D&amp;D anbd other games. There are adventures aimed at the whole family and kids like <b>Big Book of Amazing Tales</b> and <b>The Legend of Gimcrack Jack</b>. Well or dice accessoire like the <b>Dice Crypt</b> or the <b>Unity Dice Necklace</b>. Next to many other, interesting projects, which you can see here:</p>
<p><b>English Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>5 Role-Playing Games<br>
1 Gamebook<br>
1 LARP<br>
2 Settings<br>
3 D&amp;D Settings<br>
3 Sourcebooks<br>
2 Supplements<br>
1 Adventure<br>
2 Adventures for the Family<br>
3 Dice Projects<br>
2 Accessoires<br>
1 Soundscape<br>
2 App Projects<br>
2 RPG Comics<br>
2 RPG Gifts<br>
1 Save a Crowdfunding Campaign<br>
3 Various RPG Projects</p>
<p><b>German Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Sourcebook</p>
<p><b>French Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>2 Role-Playing Games</p>
<p>Article: <a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/10/13/crowdfunding-collection-121/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://teylen.blog/2019/10/13/crowdfunding-collection-121/</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-121-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-10-07-and-10-13/3673">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-121-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-10-07-and-10-13/3673</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 22:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3673</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-121-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-10-07-and-10-13/3673.rss">Crowdfunding Collection #121, including every tabletop rpg project started between 10/07 and 10/13</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Kuf - Modern day Gnostic horror OSR RPG</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Wilhelm]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/wilhelm">@Wilhelm</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>So over in the thread on goals for 2019 I wrote that I wanted to publish my new game by Easter. The Swedish release did indeed get done in time.  Translating the book into English took a bit longer than I expected, but now it is done, still 2019. <img src="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/images/emoji/twitter/slight_smile.png?v=9" title=":slight_smile:" class="emoji" alt=":slight_smile:"></p>
<p>Anyway, my new game <strong>Kuf</strong> is a modern day Gnostic horror RPG built on top of Ben Milton’s rules light OSR game Knave.</p>
<p>I have added a somewhat grittier damage and trauma system, a framework for campaigns, dangerous magic and a reworked experience/advancement mechanics a bit to go better with the setting.</p>
<p>In Kuf you play ordinary people who get a peek of what the world is really like, and get changed by the experience. The thirst for more knowledge drives them down a dark and dangerous path.</p>
<p>I’m still struggling to make a good elevator pitch of the game but in the campaign we just wrapped up the PCs:</p>
<ul>
<li>Practiced ritual magic based on the things they learned by hanging out with a senile witch in a care facility.</li>
<li>Learned to fear <em>the Firebrigade</em>.</li>
<li>Traveled to the <em>Heaths of Silver</em> where they slept with a monster to learn its secrets.</li>
<li>Traveled to the places beyond the heaths.</li>
<li>Had a panic attack in <em>the Darkest Wood</em> which resulted in the PC nurse mowing down the PC linguist with a chainsaw.</li>
<li>Managed to rescue a journalist/sorceress who had gotten trapped beyond the barrier that defines our reality.</li>
</ul>
<p>PDF: <a href="https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/276227" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.drivethrurpg.com/product/276227</a><br>
POD: <a href="http://www.lulu.com/shop/wilhelm-person/kuf-english/paperback/product-24267639.html" rel="nofollow noopener">http://www.lulu.com/shop/wilhelm-person/kuf-english/paperback/product-24267639.html</a><br>
I blabber about the game on the Nordnordost podcast: <a href="https://www.nordnordost.se/?p=1130" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.nordnordost.se/?p=1130</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 3</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/kuf-modern-day-gnostic-horror-osr-rpg/3660">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/kuf-modern-day-gnostic-horror-osr-rpg/3660</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 09:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3660</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/kuf-modern-day-gnostic-horror-osr-rpg/3660.rss">Kuf - Modern day Gnostic horror OSR RPG</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>OSR-mindset 5e oneshot dungeon — equal parts shark and whimsy</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@seanFsmith]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/seanfsmith">@seanFsmith</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <h4>An ancient sink is guarded by glowing sharks.  They say the penultimate thief of time was buried there.</h4>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>A gift</strong>? Lassiclere, a high elf midwife (who helped birth a PC) is in town. She would love a rubbing from the headstone.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Pilgrimage</strong>? The thieves’ union never mandates these missions, but good luck follows all that pray at the tomb.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Gentrification</strong>? The sink houses a gam of sahuagin.  Drive them out and we can make better use of the space.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>This short module is set in a wetlands environment near a city — perfect for your <em>Ghosts of Saltmarsh</em> campaign.  It plays out in a tight single session or a leisurely pair, and should take a group of level 3 PCs to level 4.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Time Sink</strong> is my first title for the DM’s Guild - I’ve otherwise written extensively of horror investigation and OSR absurdity.  <strong>Time Sink</strong> takes innovations from both spheres and will be a blast to play at your table, and again and again at conventions:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>the traps in the final location are randomly placed, lending it a roguelike air and great replayability</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>there are procedures and guidelines to encourage player engagement and narrative focus</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>there’s a whimsical fishwoman trapmaker who’ll feed the PCs secrets <em>and her roe</em></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.dmsguild.com/m/product/291187" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.dmsguild.com/m/product/291187</a></p>
<p>Happy to give comp copies away for listeners of <strong>Fear of a Black Dragon</strong>!</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/osr-mindset-5e-oneshot-dungeon-equal-parts-shark-and-whimsy/3633">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/osr-mindset-5e-oneshot-dungeon-equal-parts-shark-and-whimsy/3633</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 15:36:37 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3633</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/osr-mindset-5e-oneshot-dungeon-equal-parts-shark-and-whimsy/3633.rss">OSR-mindset 5e oneshot dungeon — equal parts shark and whimsy</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>What&#39;s happening with the &#39;barf forth apocalyptica&#39; forums?</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Paul_T]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/paul_t">@Paul_T</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>It seems that the ‘barf forth apocalyptica’ forums, over at…</p>
<p><a href="http://apocalypse-world.com/forums/" class="onebox" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://apocalypse-world.com/forums/</a></p>
<p>…have been down for quite some time now. There’s a lot of really valuable information on those forums, including advice, actual plays, optional rules, and links to various hacks.</p>
<p>Does anyone know what’s happening with those forums, and whether they are down for good? Has anyone heard anything?</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 6</p>
            <p>Participants: 4</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-happening-with-the-barf-forth-apocalyptica-forums/3632">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-happening-with-the-barf-forth-apocalyptica-forums/3632</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 07:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3632</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/whats-happening-with-the-barf-forth-apocalyptica-forums/3632.rss">What&#39;s happening with the &#39;barf forth apocalyptica&#39; forums?</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Moth Children | A Vampire TTRPG by Dane Asmund - Kickstarter</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I keep an eye on upcoming Kickstarters during the week in preparation of my collection. Which saw me coming across the <strong><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/cosmicmirrorgames/moth-children/" rel="nofollow noopener">Moth Children</a></strong> vampire game byof Dane Asmund.</p>
<p>It sparked my interest as I am very interested in Vampire games and storytelling mechanics and the project combines both. Including an approach to the mythology that I consider fresh and was quite new to me.</p>
<p>The game system is based on the players filling out their wheel of abilities and the storyteller having a wheel of their own with some of the difficulties noted. When a conflict occurs the numbers get compared and a result is determined. With the difficulty wheel being adjusted.</p>
<p>I am not sure whether I grasp it in full, but it does sound interesting.<br>
The only thing that I might adjust would be, to maybe set the world in a fashion that vampires aren’t antagonistic to each other and got different ways of obtaining a new moth. Maybe give it a bit of a VtM reskinning ^^;</p>
<p>What do you think of it?</p>
<p><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/cosmicmirrorgames/moth-children/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/cosmicmirrorgames/moth-children/</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 2</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/moth-children-a-vampire-ttrpg-by-dane-asmund-kickstarter/3617">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/moth-children-a-vampire-ttrpg-by-dane-asmund-kickstarter/3617</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 10:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3617</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/moth-children-a-vampire-ttrpg-by-dane-asmund-kickstarter/3617.rss">Moth Children | A Vampire TTRPG by Dane Asmund - Kickstarter</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Crowdfunding Collection #120, including every tabletop rpg project started between 09/22 and 10/07</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I present to you the new <b><a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/10/07/crowdfunding-collection-120/" rel="nofollow noopener">Crowdfunding Collection #120, including every tabletop rpg project started between 09/22 and 10/07</a></b>.</p>
<p>Following a small break, I return to present no fewer than 14 English RPGs and a whole bunch of Spanish and French ones.<br>
To start the list I’d like to direct you to <b>Little Monster Detectives</b> by Nosolorol. The project funds the translation of the Spanish games that is made for kids and with kids in mind. If you like to have a in-depth look at how it works, I highly suggest checking out the review at the GMS Magazine YouTube channel by Paco Jean. If I had children, I would have backed the game enthusiastically. Back to an older demographic, the  <b>vs. KICKSTARTER 2</b> projects does attempt to fund three micro games at one. You’ll have the choice between post-apocalyptic action, killing Hitler or fighting in mechs, which sounds like a fun mix. The <b>Charm Universal RPG</b> does offer more to read, yet it keeps the character sheet down to the size of a business card, has a universal approach and looks quite cool and colorful. <b>Ross Rifles</b> does contrast it by putting the player characters in the trenches of a war, fitting them with a Powered by the Apocalypse to survive (or not?). If you consider that to be a bit heavy, maybe take a look at <b>Drinking Quest: Old Habits</b> and combine gaming with drinking (responsible tho, imho).<br>
Which does offer a nice transfer into the Fantasy Genre. For this you’ll find the Savage Worlds based <b>Gods and Masters</b> on the one hand. It offers urban guerrilla fights mixed into the fantasy stuff. Which I find a bit dazzling but not as dazzling as electric powered steam-tech that’s provided with <b>Nuadan Chronicles</b> on the other hand.<br>
Less confusing and more cool you might like to checkout <b>Haunted West</b> for an entry into the Weird West genre. Chris Spivey, who previously gave me the splendid Harlem Unbound sourcebook, explores the weird west from the perspective of people that tend to get the short stick in the Genre. Given that I liked his previous work am genuinely tempted. Another interesting project in regards of weird alternative history is <b>Agon</b>, which offers you heroic stories in a mythic world – which I take to be a take on ancient Greece. It’s designed by John Harper (Blades in the Dark) and published by Evil Hat, thus well worth having a look.<br>
From fantasy to science fiction <b>RECLAIMER</b> sparked my interest. Befitting to current political challenges it addresses a climate crisis in the future and an eco-insurgence that aims to battle it. The game looks great and uses the tested system of Cryptomancer, thus am tempted. If you are more interested in a space punk take on the SF genre, check out. <b>Dark Stars</b> and it’s d100 system to go of on adventures.<br>
<b>Seekers Beyond The Shroud</b> is a solo-rpg and has the player explore the literal occult underground, braving various dangers. It looks great, is right in my ball park and the project in this list that has me tempted the most. Though there’s more urban fantasy like <b>Visigoths vs. Mall Goths</b>. With the Visigoths looking like Visigoths had a crash into Visual Key while being dragged through the 80s. I have neither a connection to Visigoths nor to Mall Goths, though if you do, take a look! Last but not least there’s <b>Night Shift</b>. The Urban Fantasy game uses the O.G.R.E.S system by Elf Lair Games that apparently is OGL inspired. You might play stuff like Buffy, Charmed or an Urban Fantasy setting of your own device. For which the game provides interesting classes, various playstyles and mechanics. It’s well worth having a look.<br>
There are many more cool projects. Like the gamebooks <b>Destiny’s Role 1</b> or Escape from <b>Darkmoor Keep</b>. The marvelously sparkling 2020 Glitter Dice and many more, just take a look:</p>
<p>A brief word, before the list. Sadly currently the evidence is suggesting that Kickstarter might have fired two of its workers for trying to form a union (Kickstarter accused of union-busting after firing workers). Kickstarter does in general oppose Unions, will do anything against them and spreads the usual company propaganda against them (Kickstarter To Workers and Project Creators: Drop Dead).<br>
I personally think that shitty and sucks. It did effectively dampened my enthusiasm for backing stuff on their platform. Well, that and doing my bookkeeping. It ain’t meant as a call for boycott, cause in the end it hits the creators, more something that happend, that’s of relevance and maybe worth knowing/considering.</p>
<p><b>English Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>5 Role-Playing Games<br>
2 Fantasy Role-Playing Games<br>
2 Mythic &amp; Weird Fantasy Role-Playing Games<br>
2 Science Fiction Role-Playing Games<br>
3 Urban Fantasy Role-Playing Games<br>
2 Gamebooks<br>
4 Sourcebooks<br>
2 Settings<br>
6 Adventures<br>
5 Dice Projects<br>
2 Accessoires<br>
2 Playing Cards<br>
4 Maps &amp; Minis<br>
2 Various RPG Projects<br>
2 Other games with RPG relevance</p>
<p><b>Spanish Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>3 Role-Playing Games</p>
<p><b>French Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>4 Role-Playing Games</p>
<p><b>Italian Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Adventure</p>
<p>Article: <a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/10/07/crowdfunding-collection-120/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://teylen.blog/2019/10/07/crowdfunding-collection-120/</a></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-120-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-09-22-and-10-07/3590">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-120-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-09-22-and-10-07/3590</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 10:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3590</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-120-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-09-22-and-10-07/3590.rss">Crowdfunding Collection #120, including every tabletop rpg project started between 09/22 and 10/07</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Unincorporated, a story game about small-town drama</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Bethany_H]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/bethany_h">@Bethany_H</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>Just released the public beta of Unincorporated for the price of whatever you want, on itch.</p>
<p>It’s a mostly-GMless story game with a streamlined character-and-setting creation process, meant for one-shots or short campaigns – like, say, a normal Gauntlet series.</p>
<p>The mechanics are simple and mostly familiar but with a couple of twists that fit the theme: You have 4 Reputation stats to start with: Jock, Nerd, Prep, and Goth. Dice rolls determine who gets to decide what happens next. There’s a token system that allows you to change your roll results, shift your Reputation stats, or, eventually, invent a totally new stat to reflect what <em>you</em> as opposed to the people around you, think you are.</p>
<p>If you play it, please tell me what still needs fixing!</p>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/e/ec24cd7b028e8cbabcd64e756bebd84d5cb2a135.png" class="site-icon" width="32" height="32">
      <a href="https://bethanyharvey.itch.io/unincorporated" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">itch.io</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:630/500;"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/de7c6abea55a73a20aa2e4d9b126644bafe954a1.png" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://bethanyharvey.itch.io/unincorporated" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Unincorporated by Bethany Harvey</a></h3>

<p>A game of small-town drama</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/unincorporated-a-story-game-about-small-town-drama/3456">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/unincorporated-a-story-game-about-small-town-drama/3456</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 17:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3456</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/unincorporated-a-story-game-about-small-town-drama/3456.rss">Unincorporated, a story game about small-town drama</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Crowdfunding Collection #119, including every tabletop rpg project started between 09/15 and 09/22</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I present to you the new <b><a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/09/22/crowdfunding-collection-119/" rel="nofollow noopener">Crowdfunding Collection #119, including every tabletop rpg project started between 09/15 and 09/22.</a></b></p>
<p>This time around with no fewer than 13 roleplaying games in English, with one of those coming from Germany.<br>
<b>Aces in Space</b> is a project done by Christian Vogt and his teams. The setting has the players assume the role of daring space pilots and is somewhere between Battlestar Galactica and Sons of Anarchy with some Social Media elements thrown into the mix. The whole presentation is, imho, so brilliant that I backed it, despite my personal aversion towards Fate Core. Another cool setting that does tempt me a lot is <b>Heart: The City Beneath</b> by Grant Howitt. The Deep Apiarist with its swarms of bees caught my eye and has me enticed. The system of the games is inspired or rather based on the one in The Spire and those who back it get a quickstarter upon pledging. <b>10 Workers United</b> isn’t a phantastical game but highlights the necessity of unions. The zine is a direct reaction towards Kickstarter firing workers who claim they got the boot because they tried to unionized. I backed it. If your more interested in spies and villains with super powers, you should take a look at <b>CAPERS Covert</b>. The charming setting is supported by the tried and tested card based system of CAPERS and CAPERS Noire. I am considering to back it about as much as I am considering backing <b>PunkApocalyptic</b>. The newest game by the creator of Shadows of the Demon Lord as a cool, punkrock take on the Apocalyptic genre and is, as stated, quite tempting. If you like your alternative reality less punk like and less apocalyptic, maybe take a look at the fantasy system offered by <b>Gaval Tales</b>.<br>
Back to the apocalypse, there’s <b>Libreté</b>. The games is a continuitation of the French game Perdu sous la Pluie (Lost under the Rain), and one does play lost childred. The system is a unique take on the Powered by the Apocalypse system and I do feel enticed. Another PbtA game, yet without the apocalypse, is <b>Root</b>. Based on the board game by the same name gamers will play little mice and other animals who brave adventures. <b>Under Hollow Hills</b> by Meguey and Vincent Baker isn’t particularly dark either as it focusses it’s setting on a traveling circus aiming, from what I feel, to be accessible by younger players.<br>
Then there are quite some d10 based games. Like <b>Deviant: The Renegades</b>, the newest gameline by Onyx Path to be added to the Chronicles of Darkness. The players play creatures or people who’ve been created to fight the various supernatural forces of the CofD, yet turned on their creators. Which is more interesting than I gave the first pitches credit for. <b>Scouts of the Wyrdwood Forest</b> on the other hand is a rather colorful game, in which the players try to explore some mystical woods. Where as <b>Era: Forbidden</b> focuses on the conflict between Angels and Demons using the solid game engine of other Era-games. Last but not least <b>SLA Industries</b> will get a second edition in which players have to deal with a futuristic yet dystopian city and its strange inhabitants.<br>
Next to those cool games, which really put me under the agony of choice, there are plenty more, fascinating, worthwile projects. Just take a look:</p>
<p><b>German Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Role-Playing Game</p>
<p><b>English Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>5 Role-Playing Games<br>
3 Powered by the Apocalypse Role-Playing Games<br>
4 d10-based Role-Playing Games<br>
1 Sourcebook<br>
2 Adventures<br>
4 Dice &amp; Coin Projects<br>
1 Accessoire<br>
1 Enamel Pin<br>
4 Various RPG Projects<br>
1 RPG Hybrid</p>
<p><b>Spanish Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Campaign</p>
<p><b>French Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Sourcebook<br>
1 Map<br>
1 Novel</p>
<p><b>Italian Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Role-Playing Game</p>
<p>Article: <b><a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/09/22/crowdfunding-collection-119/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://teylen.blog/2019/09/22/crowdfunding-collection-119/</a></b></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 2</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-119-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-09-15-and-09-22/3246">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-119-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-09-15-and-09-22/3246</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 22:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3246</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-119-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-09-15-and-09-22/3246.rss">Crowdfunding Collection #119, including every tabletop rpg project started between 09/15 and 09/22</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Golden Cobra 2019 is Live</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Jmstar]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/jmstar">@Jmstar</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p><a href="http://www.goldencobra.org/" rel="nofollow noopener">The Golden Cobra Challenge</a> is live and wow is this year exciting!</p>
<ul>
<li>Interesting award categories, including a distributed/synchronous one that may appeal to Gauntleteers who live and play in the online space anyway.</li>
<li>Goofy optional ingredients, including a cardboard box and fighting Fascism.</li>
<li>For the first time ever there is a guest judge, and it is a really great one.</li>
</ul>
<p>I’m on the committee (not a judge this year) and would be glad to answer questions.</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 1</p>
            <p>Participants: 1</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/golden-cobra-2019-is-live/3226">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/golden-cobra-2019-is-live/3226</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 18:32:04 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3226</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/golden-cobra-2019-is-live/3226.rss">Golden Cobra 2019 is Live</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Your Move Jam on itch.io</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Alexi_Sarge]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/alexi_sarge">@Alexi_Sarge</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>A <a href="https://itch.io/jam/your-move-jam" rel="nofollow noopener">game jam</a> about designing a game with a single PbtA-style Move is just about to wrap up!</p>
<p>Figuring out how to make a compelling single-move game was a fascinating process. My wife and I both submitted designs.</p>
<p>Her design is <a href="https://cloven-pine-games.itch.io/bring-home-the-babe" rel="nofollow noopener">Bring Home the Babe</a>, a game of bargaining with the fey to get back your stolen baby sibling. Your two stats, precision and potential, are a shifting measure of whether you are following your parents’ lessons or your own heart. Become too grown up and you’ll have to leave fairyland. Become too lighthearted, and you’ll never be able to.</p>
<p>My design is <a href="https://cloven-pine-games.itch.io/the-tabula-initiative" rel="nofollow noopener">The Tabula Initiative</a>, where you are an amnesiac black ops asset, trying to regain your memory and outrun your past. Your one move lets you rely on muscle memory to recover maneuvers from the recesses of your mind.  Strong hits let you build up a Repertoire of recovered maneuvers you can deploy without a roll. Rolling well gets easier if you increase your Programming stat—but if you let your Programming reach 4, you are a fully on-mode Tabula operative once again.</p>
<p>Who else submitted to the jam? Have you checked out the other entries? What do you think about the ways people designed within the one move constraint?</p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 4</p>
            <p>Participants: 3</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/your-move-jam-on-itch-io/3225">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/your-move-jam-on-itch-io/3225</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 16:47:55 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3225</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/your-move-jam-on-itch-io/3225.rss">Your Move Jam on itch.io</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Heart: The City Beneath by Grant Howitt — Kickstarter</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@seanFsmith]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/seanfsmith">@seanFsmith</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <blockquote>
<p>Heart: The City Beneath is a game about delving into a nightmare undercity that will give you everything you’ve ever dreamed of - or kill you in the process. It is a dungeon-crawling, story-forward tabletop RPG from the designers of Spire that focuses on what characters have to lose in pursuit of their dreams in the chaotic darkness beneath the world.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Heart is a tabletop roleplaying game, and will be released as a 224+ page hardback book and a bookmarked PDF. You won’t need a copy of Spire to play Heart - it’s a standalone game.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>RRD’s Heart is live today (and twice funded near enough). They’ve a history of getting proper lithograph printing and of hyperlinking their PDFs, and the layout here is done by the wonderful <a class="mention" href="/u/jay">@jay</a>.</p>
<p>I was one of the Heart playtesters and it was an excellent oneshot — I’d planned an inciting incident and a string of options on the way back to safety, but the players spent the whole of their time in the first haven. Our witch encased a monstrosity in the earth and forged it into a shrine; our junkmage was falsely elected as a puppet leader and summarily executed.</p>
<p>Heart has:</p>
<ul>
<li>small D10 dice pools</li>
<li>abstract Stress into concrete Fallout</li>
<li>lampshaded narrative beats</li>
<li>beautiful bodyhorror</li>
</ul>
<aside class="onebox whitelistedgeneric">
  <header class="source">
      <a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/gshowitt/heart-the-city-beneath" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Kickstarter</a>
  </header>
  <article class="onebox-body">
    <div class="aspect-image" style="--aspect-ratio:690/388;"><img src="//gauntlet-forums-storage.s3.dualstack.us-east-2.amazonaws.com/original/2X/d/d215ea9d1bf71d438cc654a6c3fa48d6155a9166.jpeg" class="thumbnail"></div>

<h3><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/gshowitt/heart-the-city-beneath" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Heart: The City Beneath</a></h3>

<p>A game of obsession and wonder in a nightmare dungeon beneath the Spire.</p>


  </article>
  <div class="onebox-metadata">
    
    
  </div>
  <div style="clear: both"></div>
</aside>

            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 2</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/heart-the-city-beneath-by-grant-howitt-kickstarter/3193">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/heart-the-city-beneath-by-grant-howitt-kickstarter/3193</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 19:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3193</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/heart-the-city-beneath-by-grant-howitt-kickstarter/3193.rss">Heart: The City Beneath by Grant Howitt — Kickstarter</source>
        </item>
        <item>
          <title>Crowdfunding Collection #118, including every tabletop rpg project started between 09/09 and 09/15</title>
          <dc:creator><![CDATA[@Teylen]]></dc:creator>
          <category>Hype</category>
          <description><![CDATA[
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/u/teylen">@Teylen</a> wrote:</p>
            <blockquote>
              <p>I present to you the <b><a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/09/15/crowdfunding-collection-118/" rel="nofollow noopener">new Crowdfunding Collection #118, including every tabletop rpg project started between 09/09 and 09/15.</a></b></p>
<p>In this collection you’ll finde 8 roleplaying games.<br>
I’ll start with <b>Hyper Light Drifter</b>. The game is based on the videogame by the same name and shares its aesthetics as well as setting. Thus the players will be exploring a post-apocalyptic world with forgotten technologies to discover using a d20 system alongside tactical combat using a mat. The whole game will come in a stylish SNES style packaging and it does look enticing. Then there’s the <b>Otherworlds RPG</b>. It’s a colorful rpg with a varied fantasy setting that has some SF elements here and there. Personally, I like the vampires, of whom some can turn into giant spiders (cool!) and it has a kind of „energetic“ vibe to it which is why I got it starred. In regards to the system it looks rather tradition. <b>Retired</b> on the other hand is a story game that sees two gamers – narrator and a player – exploring the retirement life of a former super villain. The concept sounds fresh as well as interesting and I trust Caias Ward in realizing projects, thus take a look and give it a chance. If you prefer playing heroes maybe <b>Disposable Heroes</b> is better suited to your interest. Though heroes might be a bit optimistic for glorified mail man in this card based PbtA rpg. It does sound interesting. Then there’s <b>Neotoma</b> with it’s original Science Fiction setting with some Sword &amp; Sorcery elements. It does use d12 and d20 for its system, the character sheet looks rather traditional and if you want to learn more you should follow the link to its website. Then there’s <b>SLICE</b>, a rules light game that should be approachable to kids. Well and there’s Ashes of New Earth, which aims to finance the <b>Art</b> for the game.<br>
I wasn’t actually sure how to fit in <b>SQUABBLES</b> or whether it fits at all. The term roleplaying game is used in the more educational to therapeutic sense of trying to teach lessons. In this case how to handl, react and resolve conflicts based on the methods devolped by Brooks Gibbs. It’s still a game, yet not exactly a normal „roleplaying game“.<br>
Among the other projects I am highly enamored with the <b>Story Engine deck</b>. It offers various sets of card to come up with stories including characters, antagonists, aspects, twists and more. I like the idea, presentation, did back it and do recommend having a look. Another project worthwhile checking out is <b>Homunculus Assembly Line</b>, a magazine which is created in a collaboration of 6 artists who all contribute to the project.<br>
There are many more fascinating and cool adventures, sourcebooks, dice and more! Just take a look:</p>
<p><b>English Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>8 Role-Playing Games<br>
1 Role-Playing Game Hybrid<br>
3 Sourcebook<br>
3 D&amp;D 5E Sourcebook<br>
3 Card Decks<br>
1 Magazine<br>
2 Adventures<br>
2 D&amp;D 5E Adventures<br>
4 Dice Projects<br>
2 Token Projects<br>
4 Accessoires<br>
1 Soundscape<br>
1 Enamel Pin<br>
1 Various RPG Project</p>
<p><b>Spanish Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Role-Playing Game</p>
<p><b>French Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Gamebook</p>
<p><b>Chinese Crowdfundings</b></p>
<p>1 Murder Mystery Game</p>
<p>Article: <b><a href="https://teylen.blog/2019/09/15/crowdfunding-collection-118/" rel="nofollow noopener">https://teylen.blog/2019/09/15/crowdfunding-collection-118/</a></b></p>
            </blockquote>
            <p>Posts: 2</p>
            <p>Participants: 2</p>
            <p><a href="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-118-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-09-09-and-09-15/3165">Read full topic</a></p>
          ]]></description>
          <link>https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-118-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-09-09-and-09-15/3165</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 19:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
          <discourse:topicPinned>No</discourse:topicPinned>
          <discourse:topicClosed>No</discourse:topicClosed>
          <discourse:topicArchived>No</discourse:topicArchived>
          <guid isPermaLink="false">forums.gauntlet-rpg.com-topic-3165</guid>
          <source url="https://forums.gauntlet-rpg.com/t/crowdfunding-collection-118-including-every-tabletop-rpg-project-started-between-09-09-and-09-15/3165.rss">Crowdfunding Collection #118, including every tabletop rpg project started between 09/09 and 09/15</source>
        </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
